Emilio J. Pascual

ejpascualj@gmail.com | (+507) 6025-4183 | Panamá City, Panamá linkedin.com/in/ejpascualj | github.com/ejpascualj | ejpascualj.github.io/personal-portfolio/

SUMMARY

Web developer with a background in chemical engineering and experience in procurement. Interested in back-end development of applications related to marketing technology and data analytics. Earned a certificate in Full Stack Web Development from Tecnológico de Monterrey Coding Boot Camp. Strengths in problem-solving, creative thinking, teamwork, and project management.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: JavaScript, CSS, HTML, Python, SQL, NoSQL,

Applications: GitHub, MongoDB, MySQL

PROJECTS

BM Trade Analysis | github.com/ejpascualj/BM-Trade-Analysis/ | ejpascualj.github.io/BM-Trade-Analysis/

Summary: Provides real-time data for the USD/MXN exchange rate, related news, and historical trends to allow traders to make informed decisions. This project was done in collaboration with GitHub users @danrub98, @betovaldez, and @andresplasenciaborja.

Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, FoundationCSS, APIs

Password Generator | github.com/ejpascualj/password-generator/ | ejpascualj.github.io/password-generator/

Summary: Generates a random password based on user input, ranging between 8 and 128 characters, and containing uppercase, lowercase, numbers, and special characters.

Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap

Weather Dashboard | github.com/ejpascualj/weather-dashboard/ | ejpascualj.github.io/weather-dashboard/

Summary: Displays the current weather and the forecast for a city input by user, and locally stores latest searches. Data is retrieved from Open Weather Map API.

Tools: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Bootstrap, APIs

WORK EXPERIENCE

Senior Data Analyst, Procurement Performance Acceleration

May 2021-Present

Panama City, Panama

- Created analytical solutions to bring visibility on opportunities to improve sustainability, costs, and supply safety.
- Developed innovative solutions to support stakeholders in creating strong sourcing strategies.

Purchases Manager, LATAM, Professional Services

Mar 2020-May 2021

Procter & Gamble

Nestlé

Panama City, Panama

- Responsible for sourcing a broad range of services across Latin America accounting for a total spend of \$24M and 600+ suppliers, including legal, financial, tax, brand protection, audit, consulting, and translations.
- Streamlined tax and legal services purchasing process by negotiating rates and automating transactions with over 120 suppliers across 10+ countries for a total spend of \$5M.

Purchases Manager, CAC, Brand & Business Services - Merck CH Acquisition

Dec 2018-Nov 2020

Procter & Gamble

Panama City, Panama

- Identified key suppliers across five categories (Labor, Benefits, Marketing, R&D, IT) for a total spend of \$10M and created sourcing plans, which delivered 9% savings, \$500K in cash flow, and hard currency exposure reduction.
- Transformed the labor space for CAC, moving from an outsourcing supplier to specialized suppliers for medical detailing, sales, merchandising, and administration, which delivered 25% savings and +10% increased coverage.

EDUCATION

Web Development Bootcamp, Tecnológico de Monterrey, August 2021.

Bachelor of Science in Chemical Engineering, The University of Texas at Austin, May 2018.